STEVAN BOGOSAVLJEVIC

Podgorica, Montenegro • +38267125552 • stevanbogosavljevic@gmail.com

stevyhacker.github.io



Android Developer

Summary

I am a Senior Android developer from Podgorica, Montenegro. I have 5+ years of work experience in Android development, building all kinds of applications. I have worked a lot on video streaming and live TV applications for mobile devices and smart TVs. I made small android games in my early career, and I also have some web development experience, mostly React. I participated in many local programming workshops, hackathons, contests, and I am always striving to improve my technical skills and broaden my knowledge. Furthermore, I mentored and taught Android development in two beginner courses and have been a mobile development team lead as well.

Work History

Sep 2020 - Present **Android Engineer**

Infinum

Working in an international IT agency with an experienced Android team for large-scale

enterprise clients.

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 Senior Android developer

Amplitudo

Mobile development team-lead from November 2019 onwards as well.

Taught a 6 month Android course for beginners.

Dec 2018 - Aug 2019 Android developer

GSS Media

Worked on Android and Android TV apps for a live TV/Video on demand platform.

Oct 2018 - Jun 2019 Android developer

Sportamix

App development for a youth sports networking platform.

Oct 2017 - Oct 2018 Android developer

SAFE Group

I worked remotely for a health tech startup from Los Angeles.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2018 Android & Fire TV developer

GTV Corp

Worked on white label video streaming Android applications and Android TV and Fire TV

apps. Remote position for a startup from the USA.

Mar 2016 - Jun 2016 Android & Web developer

Codingo

I worked as a developer working on android applications as well as some basic web

PHP/Laravel projects.

Oct 2014 - Present Freelance Android developer

Self-employed

I worked on various projects that come from personal references and freelance platforms. On Upwork I had some projects for blockchain apps for example.

Jun 2014 - Sep 2014 Intern Android developer

Fleka

Summer internship at Fleka, interactive design studio based in Podgorica.

Nov 2013 - Jan 2014 Volunteer Android Developer

Telenor

I volunteered at Telenor to develop an app for Telenor's SurfWisely (Surfuj Pametno) initiative to educate children about using the internet safely. The application was launched to the public in January 2014.

Education

Sep 2015 - Nov 2017 Computer Science

University of Montenegro

I studied for two years on Computer Science at the Faculty of Sciences and Mathematics in Podgorica, at the University of Montenegro until I quit to focus on work.

2011 - Present Open online courses

Udacity, Coursera, FreeCodeCamp

I have enrolled in numerous online courses and they have greatly contributed to my education. I consider them essential for learning new skills.

2011 - 2015 High school diploma

Gimnazija "Stojan Cerovic"

I finished High School in Niksic, Montenegro.

Skills

Android Java/Kotlin

I have many years of professional experience with Android SDK and various 3rd party APIs, libraries, and SDKs like Firebase, Room, RxJava, Stripe, AdMob, Leanback, Exoplayer, Google Maps, Realm, Retrofit, Parse, Facebook, Crashlytics, etc. I worked on apps for mobile phones, tablets, and smart TVs. I develop native apps in Java and Kotlin. I started using Kotlin in 2018 and can use these languages interchangeably in the same projects. I am also familiar with various code architectures like MVP, MVVM, etc.

Database/SQL

I worked with SQLite databases, used Room ORM for Android. I had experience with Realm as a NoSQL example as well.

Git & Open Source

I use Git as my code version control system of choice. I am also an open-source supporter and try to contribute as much as possible to popular libraries.

Check my GitHub account:

https://github.com/stevyhacker

Design tools

I have used various UI/UX tools like Sketch, Figma, Invision, Zeplin, Adobe XD, etc.

Web development

I have basic experience working with various web dev backend and frontend technologies in my career like React, Node.js, Laravel, etc.